Guide to the B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation at Stanford University Records SC0516
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation at Stanford University records
1949-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation at Stanford University.
SC0516
8.25 Linear Feet
Records include financial records, correspondence, publications, reports, program materials, and memorabilia.
Associated Materials
Stanford Hillel Photographs (P0072)
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation at Stanford University, also known as Stanford Hillel, was established in 1949. It provides informational, educational, cultural, and social centers for the entire Jewish community at Stanford. Activities have included folk dancing, publications, sports events, Shabbat dinners, religious activities, and a library.
Description of the Collection
The records of Stanford Hillel include correspondence, memoranda, financial records, publications, reports, program materials, and memorabilia. The bulk of the collection dates from 1973 to 1994, although there are items dated as early as 1949.
The records have not been fully processed. The "Hillel history" folders in boxes 6 and 7 include clippings, articles, memoranda, minutes, photographs, notes, lists, flyers, programs, and other materials that largely reflect the organization's activities. Further additions to this collection are expected.
Jewish college students.; Jews -- Societies, etc.; Jewish community centers; Stanford Hillel.; Students; B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation at Stanford University.; B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation at Stanford University.
- Records
  - Bates, Sylvia (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Bookstore charges (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Kinkos charges (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A - bills (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - B - miscellaneous, bills (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - BBHF (B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations) - National (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BBHF - Regional (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Benham Capital Management (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bob and bob - bills (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bulk mail (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - C - bills (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cartun, Ari (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Copymat - bills (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - D - bills (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - DWR (Dean Witter Reynolds Inc.) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - DWR Sears Liquid Assets; Dean Witter U.S. Gov't. Sec. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - E - bills (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Folkdance (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - F-bills (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - G - miscellaneous, bills (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hamilton Copy Center (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hyams, Jamie (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - H - bills (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - I - bills (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Insurance - Ludwig and Fawcett (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - J - bills, correspondence (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - K - miscellaneous, bills, correspondence (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - L - miscellaneous, bills (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Latz, Michael (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Library related - bills, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - M - bills (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - N - bills, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 0- bills (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - P-bills (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Pip printing - bills (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Pacific Corp. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Palo Alto B'nai B'rith Lodge donation (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Paychex, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Petty Cash (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Postmaster - bills (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - R - bills, correspondence (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Remittance documents (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - S - bills, miscellaneous, correspondence (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Bookstore (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Schwartz, Rebecca (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Stanford University op/maint work orders (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Stanford University stores (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Stanford Daily - bills, miscellaneous, articles, correspondence (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Stanford University - bills, correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Telephone/long distance - bills (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Faculty Club - bills (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - T - bills, miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Tax (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - U - bills (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - V - bills (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - W - bills, miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - x- Y-Z - bills (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - FedIFICA (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bank reconcilliations (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - State/SDI (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Payroll registers, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Payroll check copies, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Paychex quarterly tax reports, ending Dec. 31, 1993, December 31 1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Hillel Financial and Program Report, May, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Financial Report, March, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation budget, March 8, 1989 (+ correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Hillel Financial and Program Report - original, March, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Budget - previous to 1984 (+ correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Budget - 1975-1978 (+ correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Budget - 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Budget - 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Budget - 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Budget report - 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Hillel Financial and Program Report, March, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Budget - 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Budget - 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1985-1986 Budget Proposal (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1984-1985 accounting totals (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Budget Report - 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Hillel Financial and Program Report - 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Financial and Program Report - May, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Financial and Program Report - April, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Budget report - 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1985-1986 accounting totals (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Budgets - 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Budget proposal - 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Program and budget reports - 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Program and budget reports - 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Hillel history (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hillel history (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hillel history (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Hillel history (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Hillel history (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Hillel history (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hillel history (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hillel history (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1989-1990 program book - publicity/evaluations (binder) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1986-1987 program book - publicity/evaluations (binder) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1992 Jewish Fair sticker (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Sign-in book (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Publicity notes (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Hillel Chai-Lights - Nov., 1990 - June, 1991, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1995 retirement dinner (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Aliyah - first issues only of June 1973, Nov. 1973, Spring 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Israel Tzuris (articles and correspondence) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Members of the Tribes pamphlet - Mar. 5,1995, March, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Cohen, Jessica - grant proposal and clipping, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Hillel t-shirts (4), 4 T-shirts (Box 10)
  - Mug and pen inscribed with the word "Stanford" in Hebrew letters (Box 10)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-1996-095
  - Clippings, publications, flyers, etc., 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Issues of The Haver, for alumni of Bnai Brith Hillel Foundation at Stanford, 1988-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-1996-189
  - The Hillel Library at Stanford - Manual of Operations and Statistics, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Hillel Newsletters and Calendars, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Hillel Hat (Box 1)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2017-276
  - 50th Anniversary, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Historical Exhibit Material, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alternative Amidah, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Why Hillel?, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Budget Narratives, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Future & Leadership, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Creative Reform Services, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hillel - Old - History, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Baccalaureate Service, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hillel Board Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hillel @ Stanford in the press, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hillel Community Report, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Harold & Libby Ziff Center for Jewish Life, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Siddur Mateh Naftali, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chava Alberstein the Parvarim, 1983 Apri 19 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Guide to Jewish Life at Stanford, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fundraising, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alphabetical Files, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 2 T-shirts (Box 1)